<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Search on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/tags/search/</link><description>Recent content in Search on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 08:56:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/tags/search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/tutorials/glossary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/tutorials/glossary/</guid><description>Glossary Abbreviations Abbreviation Meaning CSO Contour Segmented Objects WEM Winged Edge Meshes GVR Giga Voxel Renderer Filetypes Extension Description of Filetype .mlab Network file, includes all information about the networks modules, their settings, their connections, and module groups. Networks developed by using the MeVisLab SDK are stored as .mlab file and can only be opened having a valid SDK license. .def Module definition file, necessary for a module to be added to the common MeVisLab module database.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to MeVisLab</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/introduction/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/introduction/introduction/</guid><description>MeVisLab Tutorial Introduction Welcome to MeVisLab!
MeVisLab is a development environment for rapid prototyping and product development of medical and industrial imaging applications. It includes a Software Development Kit (SDK) and an ApplicationBuilder for deploying your applications to end-customers.
The MeVisLab SDK consists of an Integrated Development Environment (IDE) for visual programming and the advanced text editor MATE for Python scripting including code completion, debugging, profiling and automated test development or execution.</description></item></channel></rss>