<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Search on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/tags/search/</link><description>Recent content in Search on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 08:56:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/tags/search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to MeVisLab</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/introduction/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/introduction/introduction/</guid><description>Tutorial Introduction Welcome to MeVisLab!
MeVisLab is a development environment for rapid prototyping and product development of medical and industrial imaging applications. It includes a Software Development Kit (SDK) and an ApplicationBuilder for deploying your applications to end-customers.
The MeVisLab SDK consists of an Integrated Development Environment (IDE) for visual programming and the advanced text editor MATE for Python scripting including code completion, debugging, profiling and automated test development or execution.</description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/glossary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/47/glossary/</guid><description>Glossary Abbreviations Abbreviation Meaning CSO Contour Segmented Objects WEM Winged Edge Meshes GVR Giga Voxel Renderer Components of MeVisLab Component Description MeVisLab MeVisLab consists of the MeVisLab SDK and the MeVisLab ApplicationBuilder. MeVisLab SDK The MeVisLab Software Development Kit (SDK) is the MeVisLab IDE including the text editor MATE and any tools integrated for debugging, testing and profiling. MeVisLab ApplicationBuilder The MeVisLab ApplicationBuilder allows you to generate installable executables from your developed networks and applications.</description></item></channel></rss>