<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>3D on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tags/3d/</link><description>Recent content in 3D on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tags/3d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter II: Open Inventor</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/openinventor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/openinventor/</guid><description>Open Inventor modules Introduction Besides blue modules (ML modules) and brown Macro modules, there is a third type of modules, called Open Inventor modules. These modules are green and start with the letters So\* (for Scene Objects). Open Inventor modules process and render 3D scene objects and enable image interactions. Scene objects are transmitted via round input and output connectors. With the help of these modules, Open Inventor scenes can be implemented.</description></item><item><title>Example 1: Open Inventor Objects</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/openinventor/openinventorobjects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/openinventor/openinventorobjects/</guid><description>Example 1: Open Inventor Objects &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example we like to construct an Open Inventor scene in which we display three 3D objects of different color and shape.
Steps to do Generating Open Inventor Objects First, add the modules SoExaminerViewer and SoCone to the workspace and connect both modules as shown. The module SoCone creates a cone shaped object, which can be displayed in the Viewer SoExaminerViewer.</description></item><item><title>Example 2: Mouse interactions in Open Inventor</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/openinventor/mouseinteractions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/openinventor/mouseinteractions/</guid><description>Example 2: Mouse interactions in Open Inventor &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example, we implement some image or object interactions. We will create a 3D scene, in which we display a cube and change its size using the mouse. We also get to know another viewer, the module SoExaminerViewer. This viewer is important. It enables the rendering of Open Inventor scenes and allows interactions with the Open Inventor scenes.</description></item><item><title>Example 3: Camera Interactions in Open Inventor</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/openinventor/camerainteraction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/openinventor/camerainteraction/</guid><description>Example 3: Camera Interactions in Open Inventor Introduction In this example, we are learning the basic principles of camera interactions in Open Inventor. We will show the difference between a SoRenderArea and a SoExaminerViewer and use different modules of the SoCamera* group.
The SoRenderArea module The module SoRenderArea is a simple renderer for Open Inventor scenes. It offers functionality to record movies and to create snapshots, but does not include an own camera or light.</description></item><item><title>Chapter III: Visualization</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/visualization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/visualization/</guid><description>Visualization in MeVisLab Introduction MeVisLab contains a whole toolkit to visualize data and images. 2D, 3D and 4D rendering is possible as well as the interaction with images and data objects.
In this chapter, we focus on 2D and 3D visualization and simple image interactions. Not only pixel- and voxel-based data can be visualized, but also scene objects and 3D scenes (see here).
View2D and View3D An easy way to display data and images in 2D and 3D is by using the Modules View2D and View3D.</description></item><item><title>Example 4: Display 2D images in Open Inventor SoRenderArea</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample4/</guid><description>Example 4: Display images converted to Open Inventor scene objects &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In the previous example you learned how to use the module SoView2DOverlay together with a View2D. MeVisLab provides a whole family of SoView2D* modules (SoView2DOverlay, SoView2DRectangle, SoView2DGrid, &amp;hellip;). All these modules create or interact with scene objects and are based on the module SoView2D, which can convert a voxel-image into a scene object.</description></item><item><title>Example 5: Volume rendering and interactions</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample5/</guid><description>Example 5: Volume rendering and interactions &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example we like to convert a scan of a head into a 3D scene-object. The scene-object allows to add some textures, interactions and animations.
Steps to do Develop your network Implement the following network and open the image $(DemoDataPath)/BrainMultiModal/ProbandT1.tif.
SoGVRVolumeRenderer The module SoGVRVolumeRenderer allows volume rendering of 3D and 4D images.
Extra Infos:&amp;nbsp; Additional information about Volume Rendering can be found here: Giga Voxel Renderer Change LUT We like to add a surface color to the head.</description></item><item><title>Example 6: MeVis Path Tracer</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample6/</guid><description>Example 6: MeVis Path Tracer Introduction The MeVis Path Tracer offers a Monte Carlo Path Tracing framework running on CUDA GPUs. It offers photorealistic rendering of volumes and meshes, physically based lightning with area lights and soft shadows and fully integrates into MeVisLab Open Inventor (camera, depth buffer, clipping planes, etc.).
Extra Infos:&amp;nbsp; CUDA is a parallel computing platform and programming model created by NVIDIA. For further information, see NVIDIA website.</description></item><item><title>Example 6.1: Volume Rendering vs. Path Tracer</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/visualization/pathtracer/pathtracerexample1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/visualization/pathtracer/pathtracerexample1/</guid><description>Example 6.1: Volume Rendering vs. Path Tracer Introduction In this example you develop a network to show some differences between volume rendering and the MeVisLab Path Tracer. You will visualize the same scene using both 3D rendering techniques and some of the modules for path tracing.
Attention:&amp;nbsp; The MeVis Path Tracer requires an NVIDIA graphics card with CUDA support. In order to check your hardware, open MeVisLab and add a SoPathTracer module to your workspace.</description></item><item><title>Example 4: Subtract 3D objects</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/image_processing/image_processing4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/image_processing/image_processing4/</guid><description>Example 4: Subtract 3D objects &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example, we load an image and render it as WEMIsoSurface. Then we create a 3-dimensional SoSphere and subtract the sphere from the initial WEM.
Steps to do Develop your network Add a LocalImage module to your workspace and select load $(DemoDataPath)/BrainMultiModal/ProbandT1.dcm. Add a WEMIsoSurface, a SoWEMRenderer, a SoBackground and a SoExaminerViewer module and connect them as seen below.</description></item><item><title>Example 5: Clip Planes</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/image_processing/image_processing5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/image_processing/image_processing5/</guid><description>Example 5: Clip Planes &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example, we are using the SoGVRDrawOnPlane module to define the currently visible slice from a 2D view as a clip plane in 3D.
Steps to do Develop your network First we need to develop the network to scroll through the slices. Add a LocalImage module to your workspace and select the file ProbandT1 from MeVisLab demo data.</description></item><item><title>Chapter V: Data Objects</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/</guid><description>Data Objects in MeVisLab MeVisLab provides pre-defined data objects, e. g.
Contour Segmented Objects (CSOs) which are three-dimensional objects encapsulating formerly defined contours within images. Surface Objects (Winged Edge Meshes or WEMs) represent the surface of geometrical figures and allow the user to manipulate them. Markers are used to mark specific locations or aspects of an image and allow to process those later on. Curves can print the results of a function as two-dimensional mathematical graphs into a a diagram.</description></item><item><title>Contour Example 3: 2D and 3D Visualization of Contours</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample3/</guid><description>Contour Example 3: Overlay Creation and 3D Visualization of Contours &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example, we&amp;rsquo;d like to use the created CSOs to display an overlay. This allows us to mark one of two lungs. In addition to that, we will display the whole segmented lobe of the lung in a 3D image.
Steps to do Develop your network Use the network from the contour example 2 and add the modules VoxelizeCSO, SoView2DOverlay and View2D to your workspace.</description></item><item><title>Surface Objects (WEM)</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaceobjects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaceobjects/</guid><description>Surface Objects (WEMs) Introduction In MeVisLab it is possible to create, visualize, process and manipulate surface objects, also known as polygon meshes. Here, we call surface objects Winged Edge Mesh, in short WEM. In this chapter you will get an introduction into WEMs. In addition, you will find examples on how to work with WEMs. For more information on WEMs take a look at the MeVislab Toolbox Reference . If you like to know which WEM formats can be imported into MeVisLab, take a look at the assimp documentation here.</description></item><item><title>Surface Example 1: Creation of WEMs</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample1/</guid><description>Surface Example 1: Create Winged Edge Mesh out of voxel images and CSOs Introduction In this example you will learn how to create a Winged Edge Mesh (WEM). There are several ways how to create WEMs, a few of them are shown in this example. Instead of creating WEMs, it is also possible to load existing WEMs. This was already shown in Surface Objects (WEM) chapter.
Steps to do From image to surface: Generating WEMs out of voxel images At first, we will create a WEM out of a voxel image using the module WEMIsoSurface.</description></item><item><title>Surface Example 2: Processing and Modification of WEM</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample2/</guid><description>Surface Example 2: Processing and Modification of WEM Introduction In this example, you will learn how to modify and process WEMs.
Steps to do Develop your network Modification of WEMs Use the module WEMLoad to load the file venus.off. Then add and connect the shown modules. We like to display the WEM venus two times, one time this WEM is modified. You can use the module WEMModify to apply modifications. In its panel, change the scale and the size of the WEM.</description></item><item><title>Surface Example 3: Interactions with WEM</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample3/</guid><description>Surface Example 3: Interactions with WEM Introduction In these examples, we are showing 2 different possibilities to interact with a WEM:
Scale, rotate and move a WEM in a scene Modify a WEM in a scene Scale, rotate and move a WEM in a scene We are using a SoTransformerDragger module to apply transformations on a 3D WEM object via mouse interactions.
Add a SoCube and a SoBackground module and connect both to a SoExaminerViewer.</description></item><item><title>Surface Example 4: Interactively moving WEM</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample4/</guid><description>Surface Example 4: Interactively moving WEM Introduction In this example, we like to interactively move WEMs using SoDragger modules insight a viewer.
Develop your network Interactively translating objects in 3D using SoDragger modules Add and connect the following modules as shown. In the panel of the module WEMInitialize select the Model Octasphere. After that, open the viewer SoExaminerViewer and make sure to select the Interaction Mode. Now, you are able to click on the presented Octaspehere and move it alongside one axis.</description></item><item><title>Surface Example 5: WEM - Primitive Value Lists</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample5/</guid><description>Surface Example 5: WEM - Primitive Value Lists Introduction WEMs do not only contain the coordinates of nodes and surfaces, they can also contain additional information. These information are stored in so called Primitive Value Lists (PVLs). Every node, every surface and every edge can contains such a list. In these lists, you can for example store the color of the node or specific patient information. These information can be used for visualization or for further statistical analysis.</description></item><item><title>Example 1: Distance between Markers</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/markers/markerexample1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/dataobjects/markers/markerexample1/</guid><description>Example 1: Calculating the distance between markers Introduction In this example, we will measure the distance between one position in an image to a list of markers.
Steps to do Develop your network Add the following modules and connect them as shown.
We changed the names of the modules SoView2DMarkerEditor and XMarkerLIstContainer, to distinguish these modules from two similar modules we will add later on. Open the panel of SoView2DMarkerEditor and select the tab Drawing.</description></item><item><title>assimp</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/thirdparty/assimp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/thirdparty/assimp/</guid><description>Asset-Importer-Lib (assimp) Introduction Assimp (Asset-Importer-Lib) is a library to load and process geometric scenes from various 3D data formats.
This chapter provides some examples of how 3D formats can be imported into MeVisLab. In general you always need a SoSceneLoader module. The SoSceneLoader allows to load meshes as Open Inventor points/lines/triangles/faces using the Open Asset Import Library.
SoSceneLoader You can also use the SoSceneWriter module to export your 3D scenes from MeVisLab into any of the output formats listed below.</description></item><item><title>Example 1: 3D Printing in MeVisLab</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/thirdparty/assimp/assimpexample1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/60/tutorials/thirdparty/assimp/assimpexample1/</guid><description>Example 1: 3D Printing in MeVisLab Introduction This example uses the assimp library to load a 3D file and save the file as *.stl for 3D printing.
Steps to do Develop your network Add the modules SoSceneLoader, SoBackground and SoExaminerViewer to your workspace and connect them as seen below.
Example Network Open the 3D file Select the file vtkCow.obj from MeVisLab demo data directory. Open SoExaminerViewer and inspect the scene. You will see a 3D cow.</description></item></channel></rss>