<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advanced on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tags/advanced/</link><description>Recent content in Advanced on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:58:44 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tags/advanced/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Example 2.5.2: Module interactions via Python scripting</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/basicmechanisms/macromodules/scriptingexample2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:58:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/basicmechanisms/macromodules/scriptingexample2/</guid><description>Example 2.5.2: Module interactions via Python scripting Introduction In this example, you will learn how to add Python scripting to your User Interface. The network used in Chapter V will be used for creating the Macro Module.
Steps to do Creating the macro module First, we condense the example network into a macro module and then we create a panel for that module. To create a macro module use the Project Wizard, which you find under [ File &amp;rarr; Run Project Wizard ].</description></item><item><title>Example 3: Creating a simple application</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/basicmechanisms/macromodules/viewerexample/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:58:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/basicmechanisms/macromodules/viewerexample/</guid><description>Example 3: Creating a simple application Introduction In the previous examples, you already learned how to create Macro Modules, user interfaces and how to interact with your UI via Python scripting.
In this example, you will learn how to create a simple Prototype application in MeVisLab including a User Interface with 2D and 3D viewer. You will learn how to implement field listeners and react on events.
Steps to do Create your network Start with an empty network and add the Module ImageLoad to your workspace.</description></item><item><title>Surface Example 5: WEM - Primitive Value Lists</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample5/</guid><description>Surface Example 5: WEM - Primitive Value Lists Introduction WEMs do not only contain the coordinates of nodes and surfaces, they can also contain additional information. These information are stored in so called Primitive Value Lists (PVLs). Every node, every surface and every edge can contains such a list. In these lists, you can for example store the color of the node or specific patient information. These information can be used for visualization or for further statistical analysis.</description></item></channel></rss>