<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LUT on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/58/tags/lut/</link><description>Recent content in LUT on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/58/tags/lut/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Example 5: Volume rendering and interactions</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/58/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/58/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample5/</guid><description>Example 5: Volume rendering and interactions &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example we like to convert a scan of a head into a 3D scene-object. The scene-object allows to add some textures, interactions and animations.
Steps to do Develop your network Implement the following network and open the image $(DemoDataPath)/BrainMultiModal/ProbandT1.tif.
SoGVRVolumeRenderer The module SoGVRVolumeRenderer allows volume rendering of 3D and 4D images.
Extra Infos:&amp;nbsp; Additional information about Volume Rendering can be found here: Giga Voxel Renderer Change LUT We like to add a surface color to the head.</description></item><item><title>Surface Example 5: WEM - Primitive Value Lists</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/58/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/58/tutorials/dataobjects/surfaces/surfaceexample5/</guid><description>Surface Example 5: WEM - Primitive Value Lists Introduction WEMs do not only contain the coordinates of nodes and surfaces, they can also contain additional information. These information are stored in so called Primitive Value Lists (PVLs). Every node, every surface and every edge can contains such a list. In these lists, you can for example store the color of the node or specific patient information. These information can be used for visualization or for further statistical analysis.</description></item></channel></rss>