<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prototyping on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tags/prototyping/</link><description>Recent content in Prototyping on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tags/prototyping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Step 1: Prototyping - Develop your Network</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary1/</guid><description>Step 1: Prototyping - Develop your Network Introduction In this example, we will develop a network which fulfills the requirements from the overview page. The network will be developed by re-using existing modules and defining basic field values.
Steps to do 2D viewer The 2D viewer shall visualize the loaded images. In addition to that, it shall be possible to click into the image for starting a RegionGrowing algorithm segmenting parts of the loaded image based on a threshold.</description></item><item><title>Step 2: Prototyping - Create a Macro module</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary2/</guid><description>Step 2: Prototyping - Create a Macro module Introduction In this example, we encapsulate the previously developed prototype network into a Macro module for future application development and automated testing.
Steps to do Make sure to have your *.mlab file from previous Step 1 available.
Package creation Packages are described in detail in Example 2.1: Package creation. If you already have your own package, you can skip this part and continue creating a Macro module.</description></item><item><title>Step 3: Prototyping - User Interface and Python scripting</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary3/</guid><description>Step 3: Prototyping - User Interface and Python scripting Introduction In this step, we will develop a user interface and add Python scripting to the Macro module you created in Step 2.
Steps to do Develop the User Interface A mockup of the user interface you are going to develop is available here. The interface provides the possibility to load files and shows a 2D and a 3D viewer. In addition to that, some settings and information for our final application are available.</description></item><item><title>Step 4: Review - Automated Tests</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary4/</guid><description>Step 4: Review - Automated Tests Introduction In the previous chapters you developed a Macro module with User Interface and Python scripting. In this step you will see how to implement an automated test to verify and validate the Requirements defined in Overview.
Steps to do Create a test network using your Macro module Create a new and empty network and save it as *.mlab file. Remember the location.
Use Module Search and add your Macro module developed in previous steps to your Workspace.</description></item><item><title>Step 5: Review - Installer creation</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary5/</guid><description>Step 5: Review - Installer creation Introduction Your Macro module has been tested manually and/or automatically? Then you should create your first installable executable and deliver it to your customer(s) for final evaluation.
Licensing:&amp;nbsp; This step requires a valid MeVisLab ApplicationBuilder license. It extends the MeVisLab SDK so that you can generate an installer of your developed Macro module. Free evaluation licenses of the MeVisLab ApplicationBuilder, time-limited to 3 months, can be requested at sales(at)mevislab.</description></item><item><title>Step 6: Refine - Update Application</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary6/</guid><description>Step 6: Refine - Update Application Introduction In previous step you developed an application which can be installed on your customers systems for usage. In this step we are going to integrate simple feedback into our executable and re-create the installer.
We want to show you how easy it is to update your application using MeVisLab.
Your customer requests an additional requirement to define the transparency of your 2D overlay in addition to defining the color.</description></item><item><title>Step 7: Refine - Re-Build Installer</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary7/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary7/</guid><description>Step 7: Refine - Re-Build Installer Introduction In this step you are re-creating your application installer after changing the UI in previous Step 6: Refine - Update Application.
Steps to do Update the *.mlinstall file You do not need to use the Project Wizard now, because you already have a valid *.mlinstall file. The location should be in your package, under .\Configuration\Installers\TutorialSummary. Open the file in any text editor and search for the $VERSION 0.</description></item><item><title>Extra: Run your application in Browser</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/77/tutorials/summary/summary8/</guid><description>Extra: Run your application in Browser Introduction This step explains how to run your developed application in a browser. The MeVisLab network remains the same, only some adaptations are necessary for running any Macro module in a browser window.
Licensing:&amp;nbsp; This step requires a valid MeVisLab Webtoolkit license. It extends the MeVisLab SDK so that you can develop web macro modules. Free evaluation licenses of the MeVisLab Webtoolkit, time-limited to 3 months, can be requested at sales(at)mevislab.</description></item></channel></rss>