<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matplotlib on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tags/matplotlib/</link><description>Recent content in Matplotlib on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tags/matplotlib/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Matplotlib</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tutorials/thirdparty/matplotlib/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tutorials/thirdparty/matplotlib/</guid><description>Matplotlib Matplotlib, introduced by John Hunter in 2002 and initially released in 2003, is a comprehensive data visualization library in Python. It is widely used among the scientific world as it is easy to grasp for beginners and provides high quality plots and images, that are widely customizable.
Info:&amp;nbsp; The documentation on Matplotlib along with general examples, cheat sheets and a starting guide can be found here. As MeVisLab supports the integration of Python scripts e.</description></item><item><title>Example 1: Module Setup</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tutorials/thirdparty/matplotlib/modulesetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tutorials/thirdparty/matplotlib/modulesetup/</guid><description>Example 1: Module Setup Introduction To be able to access the data needed for our grayscale distribution plots, we need a network consisting of a module that imports DICOM data, a module that differentiates between slices and another that ouputs histogram data.
Steps to do Open up your MeVisLab workspace and add the modules LocalImage, SubImage and Histogram to it. Connect the output of LocalImage to the input of SubImage and the output of SubImage with the input of Histogram.</description></item><item><title>Example 2: 2D Plotting</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tutorials/thirdparty/matplotlib/2dplotting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tutorials/thirdparty/matplotlib/2dplotting/</guid><description>Example 2: 2D Plotting Introduction In this tutorial, we will equip the macro module we created in the previous tutorial with a responsive and interactable panel to plot grayscale distributions of single slices as well as defined sequences of slices in 2D.
Steps to do Open the module definition folder of your macro module and the related .script file in MATE. Then activate the Preview as shown below:
Drag the small Preview window to the bottom right corner of your window where it does not bother you.</description></item><item><title>Example 3: Slice Comparison</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tutorials/thirdparty/matplotlib/slicecomparison/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tutorials/thirdparty/matplotlib/slicecomparison/</guid><description>Example 3: Slice Comparison Introduction We will adapt the previously created macro module to be able to overlay two defined slices to compare their grayscale distributions.
The module we are adapting has been set up in the Example 1: Module Setup tutorial. The panel and two dimensional plotting functionality has been added in Example 2: 2D Plotting. Steps to do At first, we will extend the panel: Open your BaseNetwork macro module within an empty MeVisLab workspace and select the .</description></item><item><title>Example 4: 3D Plotting</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tutorials/thirdparty/matplotlib/3dplotting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/89/tutorials/thirdparty/matplotlib/3dplotting/</guid><description>Example 4: 3D Plotting Introduction In this tutorial, we will equip the macro module we created in the Example 1: Module Setup and later on adapted by enabling it to plot grayscale distributions of single slices and sequences in 2D in Example 2: 2D Plotting with a three dimensional plotting functionality.
Steps to do The fields and commands needed have already been prepared in the second tutorial. We will just have to modify our .</description></item></channel></rss>