<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vessel Segmentation on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/86/tags/vessel-segmentation/</link><description>Recent content in Vessel Segmentation on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/86/tags/vessel-segmentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Example 8: Vessel Segmentation using SoVascularSystem</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/86/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/86/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample8/</guid><description>Example 8: Vessel Segmentation using SoVascularSystem Introduction In this tutorial, we are using an input mask to create a vessel centerline using the DtfSkeletonization module and visualize the vascular structures in 3D using the SoVascularSystem module. The second part uses the distance between centerline and surface of the vessel structures to color thin vessels red and thick vessels green.
Steps to do Develop your network Load the example tree mask by using the LocalImage module.</description></item><item><title>Example 9: Creating Dynamic 3D Animations using AnimationRecorder</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/86/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/86/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample9/</guid><description>Example 9: Creating Dynamic 3D Animations using AnimationRecorder Introduction In this tutorial, our focus will be on using the AnimationRecorder module to generate dynamic and visually appealing animations of our 3D scenes. We&amp;rsquo;ll be recording the results of our previous project, particularly the detailed visualizations of the muscles, bones and blood vessels created using PathTracer.
Steps to do Open the network of Example 6.2: Visualisation using PathTracer, add a SoSeparator and an AnimationRecorder into your workspace and connect them as shown down below.</description></item></channel></rss>