<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Inventor on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tags/open-inventor/</link><description>Recent content in Open Inventor on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tags/open-inventor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter II: Open Inventor</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tutorials/openinventor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tutorials/openinventor/</guid><description>Open Inventor modules Introduction Besides blue modules (ML modules) and brown Macro modules, there is a third type of modules, called Open Inventor modules. These modules are green and start with the letters So\* (for Scene Objects). Open Inventor modules process and render 3D scene objects and enable image interactions. Scene objects are transmitted via round input and output connectors. With the help of these modules, Open Inventor scenes can be implemented.</description></item><item><title>Example 1: Open Inventor Objects</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tutorials/openinventor/openinventorobjects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tutorials/openinventor/openinventorobjects/</guid><description>Example 1: Open Inventor Objects &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example we like to construct an Open Inventor scene in which we display three 3D objects of different color and shape.
Steps to do Generating Open Inventor Objects First, add the modules SoExaminerViewer and SoCone to the workspace and connect both modules as shown. The module SoCone creates a cone shaped object, which can be displayed in the Viewer SoExaminerViewer.</description></item><item><title>Example 2: Mouse interactions in Open Inventor</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tutorials/openinventor/mouseinteractions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tutorials/openinventor/mouseinteractions/</guid><description>Example 2: Mouse interactions in Open Inventor &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example, we implement some image or object interactions. We will create a 3D scene, in which we display a cube and change its size using the mouse. We also get to know another viewer, the module SoExaminerViewer. This viewer is important. It enables the rendering of Open Inventor scenes and allows interactions with the Open Inventor scenes.</description></item><item><title>Example 3: Camera Interactions in Open Inventor</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tutorials/openinventor/camerainteraction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tutorials/openinventor/camerainteraction/</guid><description>Example 3: Camera Interactions in Open Inventor Introduction In this example, we are learning the basic principles of camera interactions in Open Inventor. We will show the difference between a SoRenderArea and a SoExaminerViewer and use different modules of the SoCamera* group.
The SoRenderArea module The module SoRenderArea is a simple renderer for Open Inventor scenes. It offers functionality to record movies and to create snapshots, but does not include an own camera or light.</description></item><item><title>Example 4: Display 2D images in Open Inventor SoRenderArea</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/52/tutorials/visualization/visualizationexample4/</guid><description>Example 4: Display images converted to Open Inventor scene objects &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In the previous example you learned how to use the module SoView2DOverlay together with a View2D. MeVisLab provides a whole family of SoView2D* modules (SoView2DOverlay, SoView2DRectangle, SoView2DGrid, &amp;hellip;). All these modules create or interact with scene objects and are based on the module SoView2D, which can convert a voxel-image into a scene object.</description></item></channel></rss>