<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RTSTRUCT on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/124/tags/rtstruct/</link><description>Recent content in RTSTRUCT on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/124/tags/rtstruct/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Example 6: DICOM RT Visualization in MeVisLab – RTSTRUCT and RTDOSE Workflow</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/124/tutorials/image_processing/image_processing6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/124/tutorials/image_processing/image_processing6/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="example-6-dicom-rt-visualization-in-mevislab--rtstruct-and-rtdose-workflow"&gt;Example 6: DICOM RT Visualization in MeVisLab – RTSTRUCT and RTDOSE Workflow&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial explains how to load and visualize DICOM RT (Radiotherapy) data in MeVisLab. You will learn how to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load CT and related RTSTRUCT data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualize RTSTRUCTs as colored CSOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show labels next to each RTSTRUCT contour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualize RTDOSE as a semi-transparent colored overlay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DICOM RT&lt;/em&gt; files are essential in radiotherapy treatment planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RT Structure Set&lt;/strong&gt;, containing information related to patient anatomy, for example structures, markers, and isocenters. These entities are typically identified on devices such as CT scanners, physical or virtual simulation workstations, or treatment planning systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RT Plan&lt;/strong&gt;, containing geometric and dosimetric data specifying a course of external beam and/or brachytherapy treatment, for example beam angles, collimator openings, beam modifiers, and brachytherapy channel and source specifications. The RT Plan entity may be created by a simulation workstation, and subsequently enriched by a treatment planning system before being passed on to a record and verify system or treatment device. An instance of the RT Plan object usually references an RT Structure Set instance to define a coordinate system and set of patient structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RT Dose&lt;/strong&gt;, containing dose data generated by a treatment planning system in one or more of several formats: three-dimensional dose data, isodose curves, DVHs, or dose points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional objects not used in this tutorial are:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>