<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DICOM on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/102/tags/dicom/</link><description>Recent content in DICOM on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:58:44 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/102/tags/dicom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Example 1: Data import in MeVisLab</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/102/tutorials/basicmechanisms/dataimport/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:54:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/102/tutorials/basicmechanisms/dataimport/</guid><description>Example 1: Data Import in MeVisLab MeVisLab provides several pre-defined modules to import data for processing in your networks.
Extra Infos:&amp;nbsp; The easiest way to load data in MeVisLab is to drop the file onto the MeVisLab workspace. MeVisLab will try to find a module that is capable of loading your file automatically. These chapters explain the data formats and modules related to this example:
Images DICOM Data Segmentations / 2D Contours 3D Data / Meshes Extra Infos:&amp;nbsp; Detailed explanations on loading images onto your MeVisLab workspace can be found here Images A good option to load images is the ImageLoad module.</description></item><item><title>Example 1.1: MeVisLab Coordinate Systems</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/102/tutorials/basicmechanisms/coordinatesystems/coordinatesystems/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:58:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/102/tutorials/basicmechanisms/coordinatesystems/coordinatesystems/</guid><description>Example 1.1: MeVisLab Coordinate Systems Three coordinate systems exist next to each other:
World coordinates Voxel coordinates Device coordinates World coordinate systems in MeVisLab are always right handed.
The blue rectangle shows the same region in the three coordinate systems.
Coordinate Systems in MeVisLab World coordinates World coordinates are:
Global: Combine several objects in a view Isotropic: All directions are equivalent Orthogonal: Coordinate axes are orthogonal to each other The origin of the world coordinate system can be anywhere and is not clearly defined.</description></item><item><title>Example 1.2: DICOM Coordinate Systems</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/102/tutorials/basicmechanisms/coordinatesystems/coordinatesystems2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:58:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/102/tutorials/basicmechanisms/coordinatesystems/coordinatesystems2/</guid><description>Example 1.2: DICOM Coordinate Systems General Coordinate systems in DICOM are basically the same as world coordinates in MeVisLab (except for the 0.5 voxel offset). World coordinates also refer to the patient axes. They are:
Based on the patient&amp;rsquo;s main body axes (transverse, coronal, sagittal) Measured as 1 coordinate unit = 1 millimeter Right-handed Not standardized regarding their origin World Coordinates in Context of the Human Body The DICOM (Digital Imaging and Communications in Medicine) standard defines a data format that groups information into data sets.</description></item></channel></rss>