<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Inventor on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tags/open-inventor/</link><description>Recent content in Open Inventor on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tags/open-inventor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter II: Open Inventor</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/openinventor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/openinventor/</guid><description>Open Inventor Modules Introduction Besides blue modules (ML Modules) and brown macro modules, there is a third type of modules, called Open Inventor modules. These modules are green and start with the letters So\* (for Scene Objects). Open Inventor Modules process and render 3D scene objects and enable image interactions. Scene objects are transmitted via round input and output connectors. With the help of these modules, Open Inventor scenes can be implemented.</description></item><item><title>Example 1: Open Inventor Objects</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/openinventor/openinventorobjects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/openinventor/openinventorobjects/</guid><description>Example 1: Open Inventor Objects Introduction In this example we like to construct an Open Inventor scene in which we display three 3D objects of different color and shape.
Steps to do Generating Open Inventor Objects First, add the modules SoExaminerViewer and SoCone to the workspace and connect both modules as shown. The module SoCone creates a cone shaped object, which can be displayed in the Viewer SoExaminerViewer.
SoExaminerViewer We like to change the color of the cone.</description></item><item><title>Example 2: Mouse interactions in Open Inventor</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/openinventor/mouseinteractions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/tutorials/openinventor/mouseinteractions/</guid><description>Example 2: Mouse interactions in Open Inventor Introduction In this example, we implement some image or object interactions. We will create a 3D scene, in which we display a cube and change its size using the mouse. We also get to know another viewer, the module SoExaminerViewer. This viewer is important. It enables the rendering of Open Inventor scenes and allows interactions with the Open Inventor scenes.
Steps to do Develop your network For implementing the example, build the following network.</description></item></channel></rss>