<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CSO on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tags/cso/</link><description>Recent content in CSO on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tags/cso/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contour Objects (CSO)</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contourobjects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contourobjects/</guid><description>Contour Segmented Objects (CSOs) in MeVisLab Introduction Structure of CSOs MeVisLab provides modules to create contours in images. 3D objects which encapsulate these contours are called Contour Segmented Objects (CSOs).
In the next image, you can see a rectangular shaped CSO. The pink circles you can see are called Seed Points.
Seed Points define the shape of the CSO. In case of a rectangle, you need four Seed Points forming the corners, to define the whole rectangle.</description></item><item><title>Contour Example 1: Creation of Contours</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample1/</guid><description>Contour Example 1: Creation of Contours &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction We like to start with the creation of CSOs. To create CSOs, you need a SoCSO*-Editor. There are several different editors, which can be used to create CSOs (see here). Some of them are introduced in this example.
Steps to do Develop your network For this example, we need the following modules. Add the modules to your workspace, connect them as shown below and load the example image $(DemoDataPath)/BrainMultiModal/ProbandT1.</description></item><item><title>Contour Example 2: Contour Interpolation</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample2/</guid><description>Contour Example 2: Creating Contours using Live Wire and Interpolation &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example, we like to create CSOs using the Live Wire Algorithm, which allows semi-automatic CSO creation. The algorithm uses edge detection to support the user creating CSOs.
We also like to interpolate CSOs over slices. That means additional CSOs are generated between manual segmentations based on a linear interpolation.
As a last step, we will group together CSOs of the same anatomical unit.</description></item><item><title>Contour Example 3: 2D and 3D Visualization of Contours</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample3/</guid><description>Contour Example 3: Overlay Creation and 3D Visualization of Contours &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example, we&amp;rsquo;d like to use the created CSOs to display an overlay. This allows us to mark one of two lungs. In addition to that, we will display the whole segmented lobe of the lung in a 3D image.
Steps to do Develop your network Use the network from the contour example 2 and add the modules VoxelizeCSO, SoView2DOverlay and View2D to your workspace.</description></item><item><title>Contour Example 4: Annotation of Images</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample4/</guid><description>Contour Example 4: Annotation of Images &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example we like to calculate the volume of our object, in this case the part of the lung we have segmented.
Steps to do Develop your network and calculate the lung volume Add the module CalculateVolume and SoView2DAnnotation to your workspace and connect both modules as shown. Update the module CalculateVolume, which directly shows the volume of our object.</description></item><item><title>Contour Example 5: Contours and Ghosting</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/76/tutorials/dataobjects/contours/contourexample5/</guid><description>Contour Example 5: Visualizing Contours and Images &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example, we like to automatically create CSOs based on a predefined iso value.
Steps to do Develop your network Add the following modules to your workspace and connect them as shown. Load the example image Bone.tiff.
Automatic creation of CSOs based on the iso value Now, open the panel of CSOIsoGenerator to set the Iso Value to 1200.</description></item></channel></rss>