<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Profiling on MeVisLab Examples</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/57/tags/profiling/</link><description>Recent content in Profiling on MeVisLab Examples</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/57/tags/profiling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter VI: Testing</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/57/tutorials/testing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/57/tutorials/testing/</guid><description>MeVisLab Tutorial Chapter VI Testing, Profiling and Debugging in MeVisLab The MeVisLab Integrated Development Environment (IDE) provides tools for writing automated tests in Python, profiling your network performance and debugging your Python code.
In this chapter, all of these tools will be explained.
Testing The MeVisLab TestCenter is the starting point of your tests. Select [ File &amp;rarr; Run TestCaseManager ] to open the user interface of the TestCaseManager.
MeVisLab TestCaseManager Test Selection The Test Selection allows you to define a selection of test cases to be executed.</description></item><item><title>Example 2: Profiling in MeVisLab</title><link>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/57/tutorials/testing/testingexample2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:56:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mevislab.github.io/examples/pull/57/tutorials/testing/testingexample2/</guid><description>Example 2: Profiling in MeVisLab &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;This example is also available on YouTube. Introduction In this example, we are using the MeVisLab Profiler to inspect the memory and CPU consumption of the modules in an example network.
Steps to do Creating the network to be used for profiling You can open any network you like, here we are using the example network of the module MinMaxScan for profiling. Add the module MinMaxScan to your workspace and open the example network via right-click and selecting [ Help &amp;rarr; Show Example Network ].</description></item></channel></rss>